现在让我们考虑一下我们有两个鲨鱼对象的稍微困难的情况
Now let’s consider the slightly more difficult situation where we have two shark objects
在我们的形象。
within our image.
现在你和我看这个图像可以清楚地看到有两个不同的区域;我们
Now you and I looking at this image can clearly see that there are two distinct regions; we’re
一点也不困惑。
not confused at all.
但对于我们正在构建的机器视觉系统，我们需要开发一种算法
But for the machine vision system that we’re building, we need to develop an algorithm
这可以确定这里有两个不同的区域。
that can determine that there are two distinct regions here.
如果我们应用我们刚看过的时刻技术并计算时刻
If we apply the technique of moments that we just looked at and compute the moments
在这个场景中，我们最终得到的是一个区域的质心，其中包含了
of this scene, what we will end up with is the centroid of a region, which contains the
两条鲨鱼。
two sharks.
我们看到两条鲨鱼之间的质心。
We see the centroid in between the two sharks.
它无法确定它们是分开的，它只是处理所有的白色
It hasn’t been able to work out that they’re separate, it’s just treated all the white
像素以相同的方式，我们也看到边界框是围绕四肢绘制的
pixels in the same way, and we see also that the bounding box is drawn around the extremities
两只鲨鱼，而不是单独的鲨鱼。
of both sharks, rather than around the sharks individually.
我们需要一些方法来区分这两个对象。
We need some way to distinguish between these two objects.
现在，我们这样做的方式是转换图像。
Now the way that we do this is to transform the image.
所以这是我们的输入图像，我们将进行转换;这是一个过程
So here is our input image and we’re going to perform a transformation; it’s a process
称为连通性分析，输出图像显示在右侧。
called connectivity analysis, and the output image is shown on the right.
我们将此称为标签图像，标签图像的有趣之处在于
We refer to this as a label image, and what’s interesting about the labelling image is that
属于同一对象的所有像素都被分配了相同的标签。
all of the pixels that belong to the same object are assigned the same label.
因此，我们看到属于顶级鲨鱼的所有像素都标记为1。
So we see that all of the pixels that belong to the top shark have been labelled 1.
与底部鲨鱼相对应的所有像素都标记为2，并且所有像素都标记为
All of the pixels that correspond to the bottom shark have been labelled 2, and all of the
属于背景的像素标记为3。
pixels that belong to the background have been labelled 3.
在此图像中，像素值是指您喜欢的对象的标签;来描述
In this image the pixel values refer to the label of the object if you like; to describe
场景中n个对象属于哪个像素。
which of the n objects in the scene those pixels belong to.
这是一次非常强大的转型。
This is a really powerful transformation.
输入场景中的白色对象称为blob。
The white objects in the input scene are called blobs.
'Blob'实际上是一个技术术语-你被允许使用它。
‘Blobs’ is actually a technical term — you’re allowed to use it.
在这个输入场景中有三个斑点，鲨鱼1，鲨鱼2和背景，并在
In this input scene there are three blobs, shark 1, shark 2 and the background, and in
输出图像的像素值为1-3，表示它们属于哪个blob。
the output image the pixels have got values 1–3, indicating which blob they belong to.
什么是blob？
So what is a blob?
它也被称为区域，有时它被称为连通组件。
It’s also known as a region, and sometimes it’s called a connected component.
它是一组相邻颜色的连续像素，彼此相邻;他们碰了
It’s a set of contiguous pixels of the same colour that are next to each other; they touch
彼此。
each other.
当我们谈论颜色时，在我们看到二进制图像之前
And when we talk about colour, before we’ve just been looking at a binary image where
像素是黑色或白色。
the pixels are either black or white.
通常我们将从真正的彩色图像开始，第一个处理阶段是
Often times we’ll start with a real colour image, and the first processing stage is to
将该彩色图像转换为边界图像。
convert that colour image into a boundary image.
所以在这里的顶部示例中，我们有一个场景，里面有四个黄色物体。
So in the top example here we have a scene with four yellow objects in it.
我们会执行一些图像处理操作，我们将在未来的讲座中讨论这个问题，
And we perform some image processing operations and we’ll talk about this in future lectures,
将黄色像素转换为真实-或白色-以及所有其他颜色像素转换为
to convert the yellow pixels to being true — or white — and all the other colour pixels to
假的-或黑的。
being false — or black.
在最下面的例子中，我们试图在灌木丛中找到西红柿，我们要走了
In the bottom example we’re trying to find the tomatoes on the bush, and we’re going
使用图像处理技术，当像素为红色时，可以为我们提供真实的结果
to use image processing techniques that give us a true result when the pixel is red and
当它不是红色时的错误结果。
a false result when it is not red.
所以第一步是拍摄一张真正的彩色图像，将其转换成二进制图像
So the first step is to take a real colour image, convert it into a binary image where
像素值为真或假，然后我们可以应用我们的连通性分析
the pixel values are either true or false, and then we can apply our connectivity analysis
到那个形象。
to that image.
我们分配给像素的标签表示它属于哪个集合。
The label that we assign to a pixel indicates which set it belongs to.
每个像素都具有与其北，南，东或西邻居相同的标签
Every pixel has the same label as its neighbour to the north, south, east or west that has
相同的颜色。
the same colour.
这是连通性分析算法的基本部分。
This is a fundamental part of the connectivity analysis algorithm.
现在，执行连接分析的过程有很多名称。
Now this process of performing connectivity analysis has many names.
有时它被称为连通分量分析;有时它被称为blob或
Sometimes it’s called connected component analysis; sometimes it’s called blob or
区域或图像标签;有时它被称为斑点或区域着色。
region or image labelling; sometimes it’s called blob or region colouring.
许多名称，相同的算法。
Many names, the same algorithm.
这是我们原始的二进制图像，里面有两条鲨鱼，现在我们有了
Here is our original binary image with two sharks in it, and now in the middle we have
标签图像，其中像素的值取决于像素是否为1,2或3
the label image where the pixels have got values of 1, 2 or 3 depending on whether pixels
属于鲨鱼1，鲨鱼2或背景。
belong to shark 1, shark 2 or the background.
现在我可以对这个图像应用一个简单的逻辑测试，我可以说给我所有的像素
Now I can apply a simple logical test to this image, and I can say give me all of the pixels
标签值为1的标签值。
that have got a label value of 1.
我最终得到的这个二进制图像只包含一条鲨鱼，即顶级鲨鱼。
I end up with this binary image that contains just one shark, the top shark.
一旦我有这个图像，我就可以运用我们以前用过的技术来找到它
And once I have this image I can apply the techniques we used previously to find the
质心和这条特殊鲨鱼的边界框。
centroid and the bounding box of this particular shark.
现在我可以要求一个二进制图像，其中包含标记为2的所有像素，以及
Now I can ask for a binary image, which contains all of the pixels that are labelled 2, and
我有一个图像，一个只包含底部鲨鱼的二进制图像。
I have an image, a binary image which contains just the bottom shark.
一旦我将这条鲨鱼孤立起来，我就可以应用早期的技术并再次找到
Once I have this shark in isolation I can apply the earlier techniques and again find
它的边界框和它的质心。
its bounding box and its centroid.
现在背景也是一个blob。
Now the background is also a blob.
它是标记为3的所有像素。
It’s all of the pixels that are labelled 3.
所以我们可以说所有像素都等于3的图像是什么，我们在这里看到
So we can say what is the image where all of the pixels are equal to 3, and we see here
它基本上是鲨鱼形孔的背景。
it is basically the background with shark shaped holes in it.
这也是一个blob;这是一个非常大的blob。
It’s a blob as well; it’s a very large blob.
它触及图像的边缘，它有两个洞，它们是物体
It touches the edge of the image and it’s got these two holes in it, which are the objects
在前台。
in the foreground.
如果我们计算下面背景的时刻，我们会发现它有一个质心
If we compute the moments of the background below we find that it’s got a centroid which
大概在中间，它有一个非常大的边界框，四处走动
is roughly in the middle and it’s got a very large bounding box which goes around
整个图像之外。
the whole outside of the image.
现在我们有一个包含两个blob的二进制图像或逻辑图像。
Now we have a binary image, or logical image, that contains two blobs.
所以让我们计算标签图像。
So let’s compute the label image.
我们使用的函数实际上有两个输出参数。
The function that we use has actually got two output arguments.
第一个输出参数L是标签图像本身，第二个是输出参数
The first output argument, L is the label image itself, and the second output argument
是它在场景中找到的斑点数。
is the number of blobs it finds within the scene.
函数本身称为ilabel，我们传入二进制图像。
The function itself is called ilabel and we pass in the binary image.
所以它是计算出的L，它是一个图像，以及有一个值的blob的数量
So it’s computed L, which is an image, and the number of blobs, which has got a value
3，所以它说，在这个场景中有3个blob。
of 3, so it’s saying there, are 3 blobs within this scene.
有两条鲨鱼和背景斑点。
There are the two sharks, and the background blob.
那么让我们显示标签图像并进行调查。
So let’s display the label image and investigate that.
开始一个新图并显示标签图像。
Start a new figure and display the label image.
我们来看看其中的一些像素值。
Let’s have a look at some of the pixel values within that.
所以这些像素，我点击的所有像素，都是3。
So these pixels here, all the ones that I’m clicking on, have got a value of 3.
这意味着这些像素属于blobnumber3，即背景blob。
That means these pixels belong to blob number 3, which is the background blob.
这条鲨鱼中的所有这些像素都标记为1;也就是说，他们都属于
All of these pixels here in this shark are all labelled 1; that is, they all belong to
blob数字1。
blob number 1.
这里的这些像素都具有值2，因此这些像素都属于blob数
These pixels down here all have a value of 2, so these pixels all belong to blob number
2。
2.
现在我们可以做的是使用逻辑运算，对每个标签进行逻辑测试
Now what we can do is use a logical operation, a logical test on the labelling of each in
为了隔离图像中的不同斑点。
order to isolate the different blobs within the image.
我现在能做的就是显示标签等于1的所有像素，以及我们看到的内容
What I can do now is to display all the pixels who have a label equal to 1, and what we see
现在是这个场景中只有一条鲨鱼。
now is that there is just a single shark in this scene.
让我们看一下标签等于2的所有像素，现在我们看到了
Let’s have a look at all the pixels that have got a label equal to 2 and now we see
第二条鲨鱼。
the second shark.
所以现在我们得到的是一个带有单个blob的场景，这是我们遇到的问题
So now what we’ve got is a scene with a single blob in it, and this is a problem we’ve
以前见过面。
met before.
我们知道如何计算包含单个blob的场景的边界框;我们知道
We know how to work out the bounding box of a scene that contains a single blob; we know
如何计算质心，以及仅包含单个blob的场景区域。
how to compute the centroid, and the area of a scene that contains just a single blob.
因此，通过使用标记图像的这个中间步骤，我们可以解决我们复杂的问题
So by using this intermediate step of labelling the image, we can turn our complex problem
将多个地区变成我们以前见过的问题。
with multiple regions into a problem that we have seen before.
我们可以进行的额外复杂程度是使用iblobs功能。
An extra level of sophistication that we can go to is to use the function iblobs.
我传递了图像-这就是我需要做的全部-它返回了一个blob矢量
I pass in the image — that’s all I need to do — and it’s returned a vector of blob
对象。
objects.
从技术上讲，它们是区域特征对象。
Technically, they are region feature objects.
并且每个区域或场景中的每个斑点都有一个对象。
And there’s one object for each region or each blob in the scene.
因此，元素编号1是一个面积为7827的blob。
So element number 1 is a blob with an area of 7827.
我们可以看到它的质心。
We can see its centroid.
我们可以看到是颜色;也就是说，它包含值为1的像素。
We can see is colour; that is, that it comprises pixels with the value of 1.
我们可以看到它的标签;它的标签值为1，其他参数如下
We can see its label; it’s got a label value of 1, and a couple of other parameters as
以及我们将在适当的时候得到的。
well which we will get to in due course.
Blob2号的面积也是7827它是另一条鲨鱼。
Blob number 2 also has an area of 7827 It’s another shark.
而blob3号的面积非常大;我们可以看到它的颜色等于0，所以
And blob number 3 has got a very large area; and we can see its colour is equal to 0, so
那是背景blob。
that is the background blob.
让我们再次显示原始图像。
Let’s show again the original image.
我们走了，这里有两条鲨鱼的场景。
Here we go, here’s the scene with two sharks in it.
对于这个blob向量中的第一个元素，即blob数字1，我​​可以绘制一个边界
For the first element in this vector of blobs, that’s blob number 1, I can plot a bounding
盒子，我可以用绿色做到这一点......我们去了。
box and I can do that in the colour green … there we go.
对于2号blob，我可以用绿色绘制其边界框。
For blob number 2, I can plot its bounding box in green.
我也可以绘制物体的质心，我将用蓝色绘制，我会绘制
I can also plot the centroid of the object and I will plot that in blue and I’ll draw
那里有一个星号。
an asterisk there.
blob还有许多参数或属性。
The blobs have also got a number of parameters or attributes.
因此，例如，对于第1号blob，我可以说它的区域是什么。
So, for instance, for blob number 1 I can say what is its area.
我们可以看看那个特定blob的颜色;我们使用class属性，看看
We can look at the colour of that particular blob; we use the class attribute, and see
它包含值为1的像素。
that it is comprising pixels with a value of 1.
我们可以使用p属性查看质心，我们在这里看到一个包含的向量
We can look at the centroid using the p attribute and we see a vector here, which contains the
你和它的质心的坐标。
u and v coordinates of its centroid.
我们可以得到单个元素，uc是质心的u坐标。
We can get the individual elements, uc is the u coordinate of the centroid.
我们甚至发现时刻已经被隐藏起来，所以那个特殊的0,1时刻
We even find the moments have been stashed away, so the 0,1 moment of that particular
blob有这个特殊的价值。
blob has got this particular value.